# Arnold Senior Software Engineer & Engineering Manager

I'm a passionate Software Generalist with more than 15 years of experience of planning, designing, leading and implementing software. T-shaped knowledge profile. I thrive in creative and fast-paced environments. I'm a team player and love working in groups.

#### Skills

## Other Experience

Leading team rituals and group sessions
UI/UX design and writing • Micro-Service System
Architecture • Near-native English, written and spoken
Agile, TDD, CD, Remote, Mentoring

### Education

2008-2009 • Computer Science • JKU Linz 2009-2016 • German Studies, Philosophy and Psychology • University of Vienna

#### Contact

arnold.graf@gmail.com +43 664 44 85 608

## **Work Experience**

# **COMMUNITY.COM** • 2021-NOW • LOS ANGELES Senior Software Engineer (Remote)

Senior Software Developer with a heavy focus on large Front End projects.

Implemented an integration with WhatsApp used by numerous well-known artists, enabling global expansion and directly affecting company revenue.

Delivered pivotal features for the company by creating the first ever external messaging integration with Apple's iMessage.

Led several large refactoring projects that greatly improved application stability, type-safety and DX, and reduced build-times by 50%.

## RECORD BIRD • 2014-2019 • VIENNA CTO and Co-Founder

Founder and technical leader of a music industry Start-up.

Record Bird was a multi-platform music news and release notification App that acquired 200k+ users over 3 years.

Responsible for Software Architecture, building and managing a team of highly productive Senior Engineers.

Oversaw launches and ongoing development of several Web Apps, an iOS App, an Android App, several Chat Bots as well as 20+backend services.

Pivoted to a messaging platform for artists ("Sendmate") in 2018, and got acquired by Community.com in 2019.

#### UNIVERSITY OF VIENNA • 2014-2021 Senior Lead Developer

Guided and supported a team of Full Stack Engineers, delivering tools for European scientists including GIS-Apps, Data-Visualization Apps, Graphical Query Builders and ML-supported data labeling tools. Architected Server Infrastructure.Introduced modern communication and collaboration tools for async scientific teams.

# **SELF-EMPLOYED** • 2007-2014 • VIENNA Consulting Software Developer

Planned, designed and implemented 15+ applications with domestic and international clients and corporations, both individually and in teams.